

# **Bruce Page**

301.730.9365

e-mail: rbrucepage@yahoo.com

website: http://www.bigideasupply.com

vcf: Download

#### **SUMMARY:**

User experience expert with 13+ years building E-commerce and promotional marketing collateral. Recognizing, managing, and cultivating young stars into superstars. Growing online businesses through creative thinking, strategic planning and execution of strong, relevant, non-intrusive user experiences. Maintain close partnerships with stakeholders through clear, constant communication. Proven track record of managing many successful website launches that have resulted in millions in online business growth.

#### WORK HISTORY:

### Healthy Directions, LLC

Potomac, MD | 4/04 - current

### **Art Director, Internet**

- Oversee all aspects of the Internet marketing internal creative agency.
- Lead a design team, which produces 200 outgoing online direct-to-consumer marketing efforts per month.
- Collaborate with internal and external stakeholders to develop best-in-class online collateral
  including: E-commerce and promotional websites, E-newsletters, landing pages, rich media
  banner placement, broadcast emails, Social marketing efforts and online streaming media through
  all possible Internet communication channels including PPC campaigns and affiliate relationships.
- Ensure implementations are timely and effective per brand guidelines, statistical analysis and user experience best practices.
- Implement state-of-the art content management tools + work with ECP vendors to ensure smooth platform migrations. Create specs and test plans to verify platform performance and stability in staging environments prior to roll out.
- Partner with other business leaders to brainstorm, develop, and execute annual online business strategies.
- QA websites to verify coding best practices are being applied and maintained in all online creative

to facilitate SEO optimization, accessibility standards compliance and full browser support in all desktop and mobile environments. Provide recommendations and manage updates if modifications are required.

- Oversee development of SOPs to maintain transparent communication of current processes and provide reference materials to new employees.
- Create cohesive team environment and facilitate continued growth through regular internal training sessions, 1:1 weeklies with individual team members, benchmarking exercises and critiquing, off-site courses and conferences, and goal setting with regular progress check-ins.
- Provide creative consultation to Executive management as it pertains to ways we might leverage
  the Internet to expand business opportunities. Recommendations are regularly implemented and
  successful.

# **Kaplan University**

Hagerstown, MD | 7/02 - 4/04

### **Full-Time Instructor**

- Instructed a variety of classes on software packages including Adobe Photoshop, Illustrator and Flash.
- Instructed several courses on principals of graphic design, digital video production and color theory.
- Responsible for recommending software, installing and maintaining on 45+ Apple computers and file servers across the college's internal network.
- Enhanced management skills through regular team building exercises and inherent student management responsibilities.
- Was recognized by the college as the preferred instructor in the Graphics department based on end-of-semester student evaluation feedback for 3 consecutive semesters.

## Ellipsis Design

Hagerstown, MD | 12/02 - 4/04

### **Creative Director | Partner**

- Responsible for all creative executions presented to clients.
- Managed junior designer.
- Specked out projects and provided LOE assessments and quotes based on project requirements.
- Managed, built and retained relationships working 1:1 with clients.
- Worked with external vendors to deliver print and online-based collateral in various formats, always on time and within budget.
- Active member of the deign community. Joined AIGA and participated in numerous events.

- Managed all aspects of the business, including: taxes, payroll, legal and accounting consultation, business marketing and networking, Business incorporation.
- Aimed to exceed client expectations. Regularly received accolades from customers. Me being easy to work with was a regular complement, and reason why I was requested on projects often.

# mediumFUSION, LLC Graphic Arts Group

Indianapolis, IN | 2/01 – 5/02

### **Creative Director | Partner**

- Responsible for creative executions presented to clients.
- Specked out projects and provided LOE assessments and quotes based on project requirements.
- Managed, built and retained relationships working 1:1 with clients.
- Worked with external vendors to deliver print and online-based collateral in various formats, always on time and within budget.
- Aimed to exceed client expectations. Regularly received accolades from customers. Me being
  easy to work with was a regular complement, and reason why I was requested on projects often.

Career Note: Additional experience: Adjunct Professor, John Herron School of Art I Indianapolis, IN: Fall 1998, 2001 – 2002 • Art Director, Robert Feldman and Associates I

Bethesda, MD: 2000 - 2001

#### **INTERNSHIPS:**

Indiana Pacers I Conseco Fieldhouse: Interior and Display Design I designer, 1998–1999

Iris Centre for Digital Arts: Advertising and Marketing I designer, 1999

North Street Media: Advertising and Marketing I web designer, 2000

#### **EDUCATION:**

BFA – Visual Communication – John Herron School of Art and Design, Indiana University. Deans list 1997–2000.